Hossein Shahyari

UI/UX DESIGNER

Dessau-Roßlau, Saxony-Anhalt, Germany (ready to relocate) (+49) 1748611745

LinkedIn.com/in/hossein-shahyari behance.net/hosseinshahyari hossein.shahyari@qmail.com



I am a UI/UX designer with two years of experience focusing on user needs and behavior, moreover, I have five years of experience in graphic design.

My passion lies in **designing visually appealing and user-friendly websites and applications,** I use my in-depth knowledge of design standards and guidelines, analyze user and system requirements, and translate them into screen layouts and patterns in a Lean UX environment.

SKILLS

Design Tools:

- Figma
- Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, InDesign)
- Procreate (digital painting)
- Miro Collaboration Platform

Design Practices:

- Product Design
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- User Research
- Design Systems
- Responsive Design
- Graphic Design
- Web Design
- Design Thinking
- Visual Design
- UX Research
- User-Centered Design
- User Interface Design
- User Experience Design (UED)
- Interaction Design
- Lateral Thinking

- Atomic Design
- Typography
- Illustration and Digital Painting
- App Design
- User Flow
- Persona and Empathy Map
- Artificial Intelligence (AI)

Technical:

- HTML
- CSS

Collaboration and Project Management:

- Google Workspace
- Microsoft Office
- Trello
- Slack
- Jira
- Asana

Languages:

- English (Professional Fluency)
- German (Conversational B1)
- Persian (Native)
- Azerbaijani (Mother Tongue)

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer

TimeGo Dev Ltd • Full-time • Novi Sad, Serbia

JANUARY 2022 - JANUARY 2024 • 2 years

TimeGo is a startup company specializing in software development, and I have started my career as a graphic designer. Based on my personal preferences, self-training, and practices, I have gained the UI/UX designer position after a short term.

Single-handedly conducted **user surveys** and **research**, designed **Information Architecture**, prepared **wireframes**, **prototypes**, and **competitor analysis**, and created **personas** and **empathy maps** on over 20 projects across multiple industries and domains like **SAAS**, **E-commerce**, and **NFT marketplaces**. I also was in charge of designing, maintaining, and managing **design systems** for these projects.

TimeGo taught me the importance of collaboration; I have studied different design systems and started to learn **HTML** and **CSS**, and by sitting in regular meetings with the developers we have fostered a proper collaborative atmosphere.

Graphic Team Lead

H.U.M.A.N. • Part-time • London, UK

JANUARY 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022 • 2 years

HUMAN is a non-profit organization to establish diversity and inclusion among the people. My exciting journey with HUMAN started by entering the graphic team as an intern and **after 4 months being promoted to team lead.**

My responsibilities contained collaboration with the HR manager on hiring for my team, providing feedback on the UI of the company website, supervising the visual aspects of social media platforms to ensure alignment with brand identity guidelines, overseeing the graphic team's tasks and projects, and collaborating closely with other team leads and the company director to provide cohesive and effective operations.

The most exciting task and my greatest impact was contributing to research, design, and development efforts to merchandise the brand, fostering fundraising initiatives, which led to an **increase in the total fund of the company** by more than %200 in about one year.

Graphic Designer

LegaMart • Short-term contract • London, UK

MARCH 2022 - JULY 2022 • 5 months

LegaMart is an online platform connecting lawyers and people who need legal consultations globally. During my short-term contract, I was responsible for crafting various visual assets, including mascots, social media posts, advertisements, illustrations, thumbnails, posters, etc.

Through hours of meetings and close collaboration with the social media team, we have established innovative templates and guidelines for social media platforms, ensuring a cohesive and visually compelling online presence, leading to a **user engagement increase of up to %800 in less than a month**.

Graphic Designer

Self-employed • Freelancer • Worldwide

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2021 • 3 years

I have worked on multiple small and big projects such as booklets, logos and icons, posters and banners, social media materials, book covers, flyers, infographics, and more.

EDUCATION

Master of Architecture

Guilan University • Rasht, Iran

2018 - 2019

Studies around aesthetic philosophy, basic psychologies, art history, etc. However, I have not completed the program and decided to put my focus on my career.

Bachelor of Architecture

Urmia University • Urmia, Iran

2013 - 2017

Studies around color theory, design basics, forms and concepts, art movements, etc.